<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://musannagalib.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://musannagalib.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-12-09T18:17:36+00:00</updated><id>https://musannagalib.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Dendrite Inhibition</title><link href="https://musannagalib.github.io/research/2023/Dendrite-Inhibition/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dendrite Inhibition"/><published>2023-12-03T18:37:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-03T18:37:00+00:00</updated><id>https://musannagalib.github.io/research/2023/Dendrite-Inhibition</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://musannagalib.github.io/research/2023/Dendrite-Inhibition/"><![CDATA[<p>In this study,</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4Q30xnX-hcc?si=nMsWbI9-BakjvUfX" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="PhaseField"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dendrite Inhibition Strategy]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Residual Stress</title><link href="https://musannagalib.github.io/research/2023/Residual-Stress/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Residual Stress"/><published>2023-12-02T15:09:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-02T15:09:00+00:00</updated><id>https://musannagalib.github.io/research/2023/Residual-Stress</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://musannagalib.github.io/research/2023/Residual-Stress/"><![CDATA[<p>This code is in Fortran.</p> <div class="language-c++ highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="n">IF</span> <span class="p">((</span><span class="n">DYN</span><span class="o">%</span><span class="n">ISIF</span><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="mi">5</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="n">OR</span><span class="p">.(</span><span class="n">DYN</span><span class="o">%</span><span class="n">ISIF</span><span class="o">==</span><span class="mi">8</span><span class="p">))</span>
<span class="n">IF</span> <span class="p">((</span><span class="n">DYN</span><span class="o">%</span><span class="n">ISIF</span><span class="o">==</span><span class="mi">7</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="n">OR</span><span class="p">.(</span><span class="n">DYN</span><span class="o">%</span><span class="n">ISIF</span><span class="o">==</span><span class="mi">8</span><span class="p">))</span>
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="ResidualStress"/><category term="DFT"/><category term="FiniteElement"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Residual Stress]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alucone Coating on Zn surfaces</title><link href="https://musannagalib.github.io/research/2023/alucone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alucone Coating on Zn surfaces"/><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://musannagalib.github.io/research/2023/alucone</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://musannagalib.github.io/research/2023/alucone/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="abstract">Abstract</h2> <p>Aqueous zinc (Zn)-ion batteries (AZIB) are promising candidates for the next-generation energy store systems due to their high capacity and low cost. Despite their nominal performance, Zn anodes tend to rapidly develop dendrite and fracture, leading to substantial capacity loss and cycling stability failure. Well-controlled coating using organic–inorganic hybrid molecules is highly promising to substantially improve their chemo-mechanical stability without compromising their performance. We herein present a critical assessment of the chemical and mechanical stability of alucone-coated Zn surfaces using first-principles simulations. Negative adsorption energies indicate strong cohesive strengths between alucone and the selected Zn surfaces. Energetically favorable alucone coatings are further verified by charge transfer at interfaces as seen through Bader charge analysis. Negative surface stress profiles at the alucone-coated interface are mostly responsible for surface reconstruction. The contributions of surface elastic constants are dependent on the selection of slip planes and the thickness of the thin film. By considering plane stress conditions, we calculate the mechanical properties that indicate the ductility of the alucone-coated basal thin film.</p> <h2 id="tweet">Tweet</h2> <p>An example of displaying a tweet:</p> <div class="jekyll-twitter-plugin"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Check out the detailed analysis of the chemo-mechanical stability of a molecular layer deposited (MLD) alucone coating in the recent publication <a href="https://twitter.com/JPhysChem?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@JPhysChem</a> C presented by <a href="https://twitter.com/galib_musanna?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@galib_musanna</a>, Okan Karaca Orhan and <a href="https://twitter.com/PongaMauricio?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@PongaMauricio</a> at <a href="https://twitter.com/ubcmech?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ubcmech</a>.<br/><br/>Just published in-<a href="https://t.co/W6pXpqNv1A">https://t.co/W6pXpqNv1A</a></p>&mdash; MUSANNA GALIB (@galib_musanna) <a href="https://twitter.com/galib_musanna/status/1624818564128710656?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 12, 2023</a></blockquote> <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script> </div> <h2 id="equations">Equations</h2> <p>This theme supports rendering beautiful math in inline and display modes using <a href="https://www.mathjax.org/">MathJax 3</a> engine. You just need to surround your math expression with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$</code>, like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$ E = mc^2 $$</code>. If you leave it inside a paragraph, it will produce an inline expression, just like \(E = mc^2\).</p> <p>To use display mode, again surround your expression with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$$</code> and place it as a separate paragraph. Here is an example:</p> \[\left( \sum_{k=1}^n a_k b_k \right)^2 \leq \left( \sum_{k=1}^n a_k^2 \right) \left( \sum_{k=1}^n b_k^2 \right)\] <p>Note that MathJax 3 is <a href="https://docs.mathjax.org/en/latest/upgrading/whats-new-3.0.html">a major re-write of MathJax</a> that brought a significant improvement to the loading and rendering speed, which is now <a href="http://www.intmath.com/cg5/katex-mathjax-comparison.php">on par with KaTeX</a>.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="citations">Citations</h2> <p>Citations are then used in the article body with the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">&lt;d-cite&gt;</code> tag. The key attribute is a reference to the id provided in the bibliography. The key attribute can take multiple ids, separated by commas.</p> <p>The citation is presented inline like this: <d-cite key="doi:10.1021/acs.jpcc.2c06646"></d-cite> (a number that displays more information on hover). If you have an appendix, a bibliography is automatically created and populated in it.</p> <p>Distill chose a numerical inline citation style to improve readability of citation dense articles and because many of the benefits of longer citations are obviated by displaying more information on hover. However, we consider it good style to mention author last names if you discuss something at length and it fits into the flow well — the authors are human and it’s nice for them to have the community associate them with their work.</p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name>Musanna Galib</name></author><category term="distill"/><category term="formatting"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Engineering Chemo-Mechanical Properties of Zn Surfaces via Alucone Coating]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Supercapacitor Research</title><link href="https://musannagalib.github.io/research/2020/Supercapacitor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Supercapacitor Research"/><published>2020-03-23T18:37:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-23T18:37:00+00:00</updated><id>https://musannagalib.github.io/research/2020/Supercapacitor</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://musannagalib.github.io/research/2020/Supercapacitor/"><![CDATA[<p>In this study, molecular dynamics (MD) simulations have been performed to explore the variation of ion density and electric potential due to electrode surface modification. Two different surface morphologies, having planer and slit pore with different conditions of surface charge, have been studied for graphene-MnO2 surface using LAMMPS. For different pore widths, the concentration of ions in the double layer is observed to be very low when the surface of the graphene-MnO2 electrode is charged. With a view to identify the optimal pore size for the simulation domain considered, three different widths for the nano-slit type pores and the corresponding ion-ion interactions are examined. Though this effect is negligible for pores with 9.23 and 3.55 Å widths, a considerable increase in the ionic concentration within the 7.10 Å pores is observed when the electrode is kept neutral. The edge region of these nano-slit pores leads to effective energy storage by promoting ion separation and a significantly higher charge accumulation is found to occur on the edges compared to the basal planes. For the simulation domain of the present study, partition coefficient is maximum for a pore size of 7.10 Å, indicating that the ions’ penetration and movement into nano-slit pores are most favorable for this optimum pore size for MnO2-graphene electrodes with aqueous NaCl electrolyte.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="Supercapacitor"/><category term="LAMMPS"/><category term="MolecularDynamics"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Supercapacitor Research]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fire Safety Research</title><link href="https://musannagalib.github.io/research/2017/Fire-Safety-Research/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fire Safety Research"/><published>2017-07-15T15:09:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-15T15:09:00+00:00</updated><id>https://musannagalib.github.io/research/2017/Fire-Safety-Research</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://musannagalib.github.io/research/2017/Fire-Safety-Research/"><![CDATA[<p>According to the ASHRAE standard, safe level of CO is 9 ppm for prolonged exposure. According to Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) maximum exposure of CO for 8 hours working day is 35 ppm. Death can occur within 2-3 hours with a concentration of 800 ppm and within 2-3 minutes for 12800 ppm. But in our study peak CO concentration is more than 60000 ppm. The simulation by which we get 60000 ppm had been carried out from fire of stack of polyester jacket storage units with a maximum input heat release rate per unit area (HRRPUA) of 1500kw/m2 over a 50m2 area. It indicates that how severe real situation is. Because in real garment and textile industry can have cloth stocks larger than 50 m2. So preventive measures is must to save life of people as we know smoke is more dangerous than the fire itself. In most of the fire incidents people were killed due to inhalation of smoke. Our study shows the propagation behavior of CO smoke and different ways to reduce the propagation.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="code"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fire Safety Research]]></summary></entry></feed>